[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "correct-answer": 3,
    "question": "Who is the legendary heroine who swam across Lake Rotorua to meet Tutanekai?",
    "answer1": "Maui",
    "answer2": "Mauo",
    "answer3": "Hinemoa",
    "answer4": "Taupo"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "correct-answer": 1,
    "question": "What is the name for the traditional method of trade training in NZ?",
    "answer1": "Apprenticeships",
    "answer2": "Friendships",
    "answer3": "Trade-learning",
    "answer4": "Traderships"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "correct-answer": 1,
    "question": "What is a poi?",
    "answer1": "A light ball on a string",
    "answer2": "A dance",
    "answer3": "A song",
    "answer4": "A carved piece of stone"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "correct-answer": 2,
    "question": "How many Maori chiefs signed the Treaty of Waitangi at Waitangi?",
    "answer1": "23",
    "answer2": "43",
    "answer3": "63",
    "answer4": "83"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "correct-answer": 1,
    "question": "Where is the largest stretch of flat land in NZ?",
    "answer1": "Canterbury Plains",
    "answer2": "Rotorua",
    "answer3": "Taupo",
    "answer4": "Nelson"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "correct-answer": 1,
    "question": "What is the name of the largest peninsula north of Thames?",
    "answer1": "Coromandel Peninsula",
    "answer2": "Auckland Peninsula",
    "answer3": "Thames Peninsula",
    "answer4": "Christchurch Peninsula"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "correct-answer": 4,
    "question": "Which common household pet can become a wild pest which kills native birds?",
    "answer1": "Dogs",
    "answer2": "Fish",
    "answer3": "Guinea pigs",
    "answer4": "Cats"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "correct-answer": 3,
    "question": "Jerusalem is situated near which NZ river??",
    "answer1": "Waipa",
    "answer2": "Waikato",
    "answer3": "Whanganui",
    "answer4": "Wairoa"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "correct-answer": 3,
    "question": "What electrical devices to incapacitate people have been used by the NZ Police since 2006?",
    "answer1": "Guns",
    "answer2": "Fishing rods",
    "answer3": "Tasers",
    "answer4": "Shockwavers"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "correct-answer": 4,
    "question": "What does e noho mean?",
    "answer1": "Nod",
    "answer2": "Sit down",
    "answer3": "Lie down",
    "answer4": "Peace"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "correct-answer": 1,
    "question": "Who wrote 'Slice of Heaven', which became the tourist industry anthem?",
    "answer1": "Dave Dobbyn",
    "answer2": "Tim Finn",
    "answer3": "John Lennon",
    "answer4": "Russel Crowe"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "correct-answer": 2,
    "question": "What attracted Chinese immigrants to NZ from the 1860s?",
    "answer1": "Living costs",
    "answer2": "Goldmining",
    "answer3": "Family",
    "answer4": "Enjoyment"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "correct-answer": 1,
    "question": "Which NZ city is one of the few cities in the world to have harbours on two separate bodies of water?",
    "answer1": "Auckland",
    "answer2": "Christchurch",
    "answer3": "Wellington",
    "answer4": "Hamilton"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "correct-answer": 2,
    "question": "What is the only known wingless bird?",
    "answer1": "The kiwi",
    "answer2": "The moa",
    "answer3": "The kakapo",
    "answer4": "The eagle"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "correct-answer": 1,
    "question": "What was the period in the 1930s called, when there was high unemployment and poverty?",
    "answer1": "Depression",
    "answer2": "Low",
    "answer3": "Cry",
    "answer4": "Negative"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "correct-answer": 1,
    "question": "Which of these lives the longest?",
    "answer1": "Orange Roughy",
    "answer2": "Tuatara",
    "answer3": "Royal Albatross",
    "answer4": "Eagle"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "correct-answer": 2,
    "question": "Which famous natural wonder was destroyed by a volcanic eruption in 1886?",
    "answer1": "The Sky Tower in Auckland",
    "answer2": "The Pink and White Terraces in Rotorua",
    "answer3": "Lake Taupo",
    "answer4": "Geronimo Place"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "correct-answer": 3,
    "question": "Chew Chong brought wealth to Taranaki through exporting what to England?",
    "answer1": "Sheep",
    "answer2": "Timber",
    "answer3": "Butter",
    "answer4": "Coal"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "correct-answer": 4,
    "question": "How many species of ants are native to NZ?",
    "answer1": "None",
    "answer2": "One",
    "answer3": "Five",
    "answer4": "Ten"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "correct-answer": 2,
    "question": "What simple child's toy has become a symbol of kiwiana?",
    "answer1": "Thomas the Tank Engine",
    "answer2": "The Buzzy Bee",
    "answer3": "The Hot Wheels Car",
    "answer4": "Jellycar"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "correct-answer": 1,
    "question": "What are Moko?",
    "answer1": "Traditional Maori tattoos",
    "answer2": "Traditional Maori art",
    "answer3": "Traditional Maori greetings",
    "answer4": "Traditional Maori food"
  }
]